Register of the Robert Daniel Murphy papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Political Adviser I, 1944-1949
  - Correspondence
    - Cannon, John K., 1945 (Folder 22)
    - Chapin, Selden, 1946 (Folder 23)
    - Clark, Mark, 1945-1947 (Folder 24)
    - Clay, Lucius, 1947-1949 (Folder 25)
    - Clayton, William L., 1944-1947 (Folder 26)
    - Cronan, Richard J., 1945 (Folder 27)
    - Culbert, F.P., 1948-1949 (Folder 28)
    - Davies, Joseph, 1945 (Folder 29)
    - DeCourcy, William C., 1946 (Folder 30)
    - Donovan, William, 1945-1948 (Folder 31)
    - Douglas, Lewis, 1949 (Folder 32)
    - Draper, W.H., Jr., 1945-1949 (Folder 33)
    - Dulles, Allen, 1944-1948 (Folder 34)
    - Dulles, John Foster, 1947-1948 (Folder 35)
    - Dunn, James, 1944-1946 (Folder 36)
    - Durbrow, Elbridge, 1945 (Folder 37)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1945-1948 (Folder 38)
    - Esteva, Georges, 1948 (Folder 39)
    - Farley, James, 1945-1949 (Folder 40)
    - Forrestal, James V., 1946-1947 (Folder 41)
    - Fullerton, Hugh, 1946 (Folder 42)
    - Galbraith, John K., 1947 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Gellhorn, Martha, 1946-1947 (Folder 2)
    - Gerten, Nicholas, 1944-1945 (Folder 3)
    - Gibson, Hugh, 1948-1949 (Folder 4)
    - Giraud, Henri, 1944 (Folder 5)
    - Goethals, Georges, 1946 (Folder 6)
    - Gray, Cecil, 1946 (Folder 7)
    - Grew, Joseph C., 1944-1945 (Folder 8)
    - Gribanov, 1947 (Folder 9)
    - Gross, Ernest, 1949 (Folder 10)
    - Gruenther, Alfred, 1944-1948 (Folder 11)
    - Hardy, Simone, 1948 (Folder 12)
    - Harley, F.L., 1944-1945 (Folder 13)
    - Harnischfeger, Walter, 1948 (Folder 14)
    - Harriman, W. Averell, 1949 (Folder 15)
    - Harris, David, 1946 (Folder 16)
    - Henry-Haye, Gaston, 1945 (Folder 17)
    - Hickerson, John, 1948 (Folder 18)
    - Holmes, Julius, 1944-1945 (Folder 19)
    - Hoover, Herbert C., 1947-1949 (Folder 20)
    - Hopkins, Harry, 1945 (Folder 21)
    - Hrones, John, 1946-1949 (Folder 22)
    - Hulick, Charles, 1948 (Folder 23)
    - Hull, Cordell, 1944-1949 (Folder 24)
    - Jacobs, Joseph, 1949 (Folder 25)
    - Jessup, Philip, 1948 (Folder 26)
    - Jones, J. Wesley, 1945 (Folder 27)
    - Kennan, George F., 1947-1948 (Folder 28)
    - Keyes, Geoffrey, 1949 (Folder 29)
    - King, David, 1947 (Folder 30)
    - Knapp, J. Burke, 1949 (Folder 31)
    - Krantz, Frederick, 1947 (Folder 32)
    - Krantz, Marian, 1947 (Folder 33)
    - LaFollette, Charles, 1949 (Folder 34)
    - Langer, William, 1947 (Folder 35)
    - Laukhuff, Perry, 1949 (Folder 36)
    - Leahy, William, 1945-1949 (Folder 37)
    - Lemaigre-Dubreuil, Jacques, 1948-1949 (Folder 38)
    - LeMay, Curtis, 1948 (Folder 39)
    - Likeman, J.L., 1947 (Folder 40)
    - Long, Breckinridge, 1944 (Folder 41)
    - Lovett, Robert, 1947-1949 (Folder 42)
    - Lynch, Robert, 1944-1945 (Folder 43)
    - Lyon, Frederick B., 1946 (Folder 44)
    - MacArthur, Douglas, II, 1946-1947 (Folder 45)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 1945 (Folder 46)
    - Macmillan, Harold, 1944-1947 (Folder 47)
    - Magruder, Carter, 1949 (Folder 48)
    - Marshall, George, 1945-1949 (Folder 49)
    - Mast, L., 1945 (Folder 50)
    - Matthews, H. Freeman, 1944-1947 (Folder 51)
    - McCarthy, Frank, 1945 (Folder 52)
    - McCloy, John J., 1949 (Folder 53)
    - McGraw, James, 1948-1949 (Folder 54)
    - Mefret, Noel, 1945-1949 (Folder 55)
    - Merigeault, Rene, 1945 (Folder 56)
    - Miao, P.C., 1949 (Folder 57)
    - Murphy, Raymond, 1946 (Folder 58)
    - Nabokoff, Nicolas, 1947 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Newman, James, 1948 (Folder 2)
    - Nizer, Louis, 1945 (Folder 3)
    - North African Economic Board, 1949 (Folder 4)
    - O'Brien, William G., 1945-1949 (Folder 5)
    - Offie, Carmel, 1944-1949 (Folder 6)
    - Oppenheimer, Fritz, 1949 (Folder 7)
    - Pasquier, Pierre du, 1946 (Folder 8)
    - Patton, George, 1945 (Folder 9)
    - Pauley, Edwin W., 1946 (Folder 10)
    - Pendar, Kenneth, 1944-1946 (Folder 11)
    - Peurifoy, John, 1948-1949 (Folder 12)
    - Pinkley, Virgil, 1947 (Folder 13)
    - Pollock, James, 1947 (Folder 14)
    - Poole, DeWitt, 1946 (Folder 15)
    - Pope, Maurice, 1946 (Folder 16)
    - Prud'homme, Hector, 1949 (Folder 17)
    - Reber, Samuel, 1945-1949 (Folder 18)
    - Riddleberger, James, 1946-1949 (Folder 19)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1946 (Folder 20)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1944 (Folder 21)
    - Rostow, W.W., 1947 (Folder 22)
    - Royall, Kenneth, 1947-1948 (Folder 23)
    - Rusk, Dean, 1949 (Folder 24)
    - Russell, Donald, 1946 (Folder 25)
    - Saint Hardouin, Jacques T. de, 1945-1947 (Folder 26)
    - Saltzman, Charles, 1947-1949 (Folder 27)
    - Schneider, Douglas, 1945 (Folder 28)
    - Sevareid, Eric, 1944 (Folder 29)
    - Shaw, G. Howland, 1944 (Folder 30)
    - Smith, W. Bedell, 1945 (Folder 31)
    - Spellman, Francis Cardinal, 1945-1947 (Folder 32)
    - Spofford, Charles, 1946-1947 (Folder 33)
    - Steelman, John, 1949 (Folder 34)
    - Steingut, Leo, 1944-1945 (Folder 35)
    - Stettinius, Edward, Jr., 1944-1946 (Folder 36)
    - Stimson, Henry, 1945 (Folder 37)
    - Stone, Donald, 1945 (Folder 38)
    - Stone, William E., 1948 (Folder 39)
    - Strang, William, 1945-1947 (Folder 40)
    - Sumner, Edward, 1944-1947 (Folder 41)
    - Swope, Herbert Bayard, 1949 (Folder 42)
    - Symington, W. Stuart, 1947 (Folder 43)
    - Szymczak, M.S., 1947 (Folder 44)
    - Taylor, Maxwell, 1948-1949 (Folder 45)
    - Truman, Harry, 1945-1947 (Folder 46)
    - Tuck, S. Pinkney, 1949 (Folder 47)
    - Tully, Grace, 1945 (Folder 48)
    - Tuthill, John, 1947-1948 (Folder 49)
    - U.S. Department of State, 1945-1949 (Folder 50)
    - Vandenberg, Arthur H., 1947 (Folder 51)
    - Vaughn, Harry, 1947 (Folder 52)
    - Vuillien, Charles, 1946-1949 (Folder 53)
    - Vyshinsky, Andrei, 1947 (Folder 54)
    - Wallner, Woodruff, 1947 (Folder 55)
    - Webb, James E., 1949 (Folder 56)
    - Weygand, Jacques, 1946 (Folder 57)
    - Wickersham, Neil, 1946 (Folder 58)
  - Office file as member of U.S. delegation, Council of Foreign Ministers, Moscow, March-April, 1947
    - General (Box 60, Folder 1-2)
    - Proceedings (Folder 3)
    - Reports (Folder 4)
    - Working papers
      - Coal (Folder 5)
      - Demilitarization (Folder 6)
      - Democratization (Folder 7)
      - Denazification (Box 61, Folder 1)
      - Displaced persons (Folder 2)
      - German assets in Austria (Folder 3)
      - Germany as an economic unit (Folder 4)
      - Inter-Allied Reparations Agency (Folder 5)
      - Limitation of occupation forces (Folder 6)
      - Polish-German frontier (Folder 7)
      - Preparation of German Peace Treaty (Box 62, Folder 1-2)
      - Prisoners of war (Folder 3)
      - Provisional government (of Germany) (Folder 4)
      - Reparations (Box 63, Folder 1)
      - Repatriation of Soviet citizens (Folder 2)
      - Ruhr-Rhineland (Folder 3)
      - Saar (Folder 4)
      - Territorial reorganization (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - Treaty - Disarmament and demilitarization (Folder 2)
      - Trieste (Folder 3)
      - United Nations property in Germany (Folder 4)
  - Office file as member of U.S. delegation, Council of Foreign Ministers, London, November-December, 1947
    - General (Box 65, Folder 1-3)
    - Working papers
      - Austria (Folder 4)
      - Economic principles (Folder 5)
      - Germany (Folder 6)
      - Germany (Box 66, Folder 1-2)
      - Peace treaty (Folder 3)
      - Provisional government (Folder 4)
      - Reparations (Folder 5)
  - Office file as member of the U.S. delegation, Council of Foreign Ministers, Paris, May-June, 1949
    - General (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Preparatory papers (Folder 2-11)
    - Working papers
      - Austria (Box 68, Folder 1)
      - Berlin (Folder 2-4)
      - Quadripartite draft (Folder 5)
  - Office file as political adviser, Office of the Military Government of the United States (OMGUS)
    - General (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Background information (Folder 2)
    - Documents - German government (Folder 3-7)
      - Memoranda, correspondence Copies of captured German documents, related to German-Russian relations, the North African Campaign, and the conduct of the war; including agreements and communications between Russian and German representatives, communiques from Friedrich von Schulenberg, Joachim von Ribbentrop, and V.M. Molotov. Also included are memoranda (in English) to Robert Murphy describing the documents. Not all of the documents are complete in this collection, but are available on microfilm in the National Archives, 1938-1943
      - Minutes (incomplete). Meetings of Adolf Hitler and his staff on the conduct of the war, 1942-1945
        - Parts 29-34 (Folder 8)
        - Parts 35-40 (Box 70, Folder 1)
        - Parts 44-53 (Folder 2)
      - Reports. Evaluation of the Soviet secret service until the summer of as observed by the German Front Aufklaerungstruppe III. Report is based on interrogations and captured Russian field orders. English translation entitled, "Organization and Mission of the Soviet Secret Service", 1944 (Folder 3)
    - Memoranda, including copies of memoranda, 1944-1946 (Folder 4-5)
    - Reports
      - Agreements on Germany (Box 71, Folder 1)
      - Certain International and U.S. Policy Documents Regarding Germany (Folder 2)
      - Chronologic Tables on Western Germany, Part I (Folder 3)
      - Chronologic Tables on Western Germany, Part II (Folder 4)
      - Decartelization Program in Germany (Folder 5)
      - Discussion of Possible Constitutional Provisions for a German Federal Government (Folder 6)
      - Documented Chronology on Political Developments Regarding Germany (Folder 7)
      - Documents on German Unity (Folder 8)
      - Economic Prospects of the Russian Zone and Russian Attitude Toward German Unity (Folder 9)
      - History of the Office of Military Government for Germany to, 1945 (Folder 10)
      - International Regimes for Cities (Box 72, Folder 1)
      - Inter-Zonal Transit Rights and Movement of Forces to Occupation Zones (Folder 2)
      - Military Government Law (Folder 3)
      - Principal Allied Economic Agreements on Germany and Control Agencies (Folder 4)
      - Property Control (Folder 5)
      - Reparations (Folder 6)
      - Summary of Multipartite Agreements and Disagreements on Germany
        - Part I (Folder 7)
        - Part II (Box 73, Folder 1)
      - Summary of Multipartite Agreements and Disagreements on Germany (Folder 2)
      - Summary of U.S. Statements and Proposals on German Government (Folder 3)
      - U.S. Policy - Germany (Folder 4)
  - Office file as member of U.S. delegation, Tripartite Talks, London, February-April, 1948
    - General (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Memoranda (Folder 2)
    - Reports
      - Benelux (Folder 3)
      - ECA Aid to Bizone (Folder 4)
      - European Recovery Program (Folder 5)
      - German Inventory and Security (Folder 6)
      - Germany (Box 75, Folder 1)
      - Political and Economic Organization (Folder 2)
      - Protection of Allied Interests (Folder 3)
      - Reparations (Box 76, Folder 1)
      - Ruhr (Folder 2)
      - Security (Folder 3)
      - Territorial Arrangement (Folder 4)
      - Trizonia (Folder 5)
  - Subject file. Memoranda, reports, correspondence, printed material, 1944-1949
    - Allied High Commission for Germany (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Allied Military Missions (Folder 2)
    - Baudouin, Paul (Folder 3)
    - Economic cooperation - U.S. and Germany (Folder 4)
    - European Advisory Commission (Folder 5)
    - Field, Noel (Folder 6)
    - Flandin, Pierre (Folder 7)
    - France
      - General, including copies of correspondence between Jesse Straus and Franklin D. Roosevelt (Folder 8)
      - Foreign Legion (Folder 9)
    - Germany - Foreign relations, including copies of minutes of meetings of German leaders; interrogation records (Folder 10)
    - Hitler, Adolf (Folder 11)
    - Independent League for European Cooperation (Folder 12)
    - Military Government Conference, August, 1945 (Folder 13)
    - Miscellany (Folder 14-15)
  - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (U.S.S.R.) (Folder 16)
  - United States - Foreign relations
    - France (Folder 17)
    - Germany (Folder 18)
  - Voice of America - Russian program (Folder 19)
- Ambassadorships I, Department of State, 1949-1959
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, and subject files collected by Robert Murphy during his tenure as Director, Office for Germany and Austria, Department of State; Ambassador to Belgium; Ambassador to Japan; Assistant Secretary of State for United Nations Affairs; Deputy Secretary of State; and Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs; arranged by form.
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - 1950-1952 (Box 78, Folder 1-9)
      - 1952-1953 (Box 79, Folder 1-11)
      - 1953 (Box 80, Folder 1-12)
      - 1953-1954 (Box 81, Folder 1-14)
      - 1955 (Box 82, Folder 1-14)
      - 1956-1958 (Box 83, Folder 1-14)
      - 1958-1959 (Box 84, Folder 1-14)
      - 1959 (Box 85, Folder 1-15)
      - 1959 (Box 86, Folder 1-16)
    - Acheson, Alice, 1951 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Acheson, Dean, 1950-1959 (Folder 2)
    - Achilles, Theodore, 1951-1959 (Folder 3)
    - Adams, Ware, 1959 (Folder 4)
    - Aldrich, Winthrop, 1953-1955 (Folder 5)
    - Allen, George, 1956-1959 (Folder 6)
    - Allison, John, 1951-1953 (Folder 7)
    - Alphand, Herve, 1959 (Folder 8)
    - Alverson, Lyle, 1956-1959 (Folder 9)
    - Armour, Norman, 1958-1959 (Folder 10)
    - Armstrong, Clare, 1958 (Folder 11)
    - Arneson, R. Gordon, 1951 (Folder 12)
    - Auchincloss, Hugh, 1953 (Folder 13)
    - Baldridge, H. Malcolm, 1959 (Folder 14)
    - Baldwin, Roger, 1953-1959 (Folder 15)
    - Baruch, Bernard, 1953-1959 (Folder 16)
    - Battle, Lucius, 1949-1959 (Folder 17)
    - Beam, Jacob, 1950-1959 (Folder 18)
    - Berenson, Lawrence, 1959 (Folder 19)
    - Berle, Adolf, 1952 (Folder 20)
    - Bertrand, Henri, 1957-1959 (Folder 21)
    - Bess, Demaree, 1954 (Folder 22)
    - Bohlen, Charles, 1953 (Folder 23)
    - Bond, Niles, 1952 (Folder 24)
    - Bonsal, Philip, 1953 (Folder 25)
    - Bowie, Robert, 1951 (Folder 26)
    - Bradley, Omar, 1950 (Folder 27)
    - Briggs, Ellis, 1959 (Folder 28)
    - Brockman, H.A., 1958-1959 (Folder 29)
    - Brooks, Russell, 1950 (Folder 30)
    - Brown, Mr. and Mrs. Irving, 1951-1958 (Folder 31)
    - Brown, Lestrade, 1953-1957 (Folder 32)
    - Buck, Pearl, 1952 (Folder 33)
    - Bullitt, William C., 1950-1957 (Folder 34)
    - Burke, Arleigh, 1959 (Folder 35)
    - Butz, Earl, 1957-1959 (Folder 36)
    - Byers, Clovis, 1959 (Folder 37)
    - Byrnes, James, 1950-1959 (Folder 38)
    - Byroade, Henry, 1951 (Folder 39)
    - Cabot, Thomas, 1951 (Folder 40)
    - Capella, Basil, 1953 (Folder 41)
    - Carter, Henry, 1951-1959 (Folder 42)
    - Chang Chun, 1953 (Folder 43)
    - Chiang Kai-shek, 1953 (Folder 44)
    - Clark, Mark, 1951-1959 (Folder 45)
    - Clay, Lucius, 1950-1958 (Folder 46)
    - Corrigan, Robert, 1949-1958 (Folder 47)
    - Cowen, Myron, 1953 (Folder 48)
    - Cramer, Benjamin, 1953 (Folder 49)
    - Cronan, Richard, 1950-1959 (Folder 50)
    - Crowe, Philip, 1959 (Folder 51)
    - Culbertson, William S., 1953-1954 (Folder 52)
    - Cummings, Nathan, 1952-1958 (Folder 53)
    - Czapski, Emeric, 1953-1959 (Folder 54)
    - Darlan, Alain, 1955 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Davies, John Paton, 1951 (Folder 2)
    - Deak, Francis, 1958-1959 (Folder 3)
    - DeCastro, Ralph, 1952-1953 (Folder 4)
    - D'Esterno, Mira, 1952-1957 (Folder 5)
    - Deverall, Richard, 1953-1959 (Folder 6)
    - Dobyns, Thomas G., 1951 (Folder 7)
    - Donovan, William, 1952 (Folder 8)
    - Doolittle, J.H., 1952 (Folder 9)
    - Dooman, Eugene, 1953 (Folder 10)
    - Dorn, Frank, 1953 (Folder 11)
    - Douglas, Lewis, 1950-1959 (Folder 12)
    - Douglas, William O., 1952-1959 (Folder 13)
    - Doyle, Albert M., 1950 (Folder 14)
    - Draper, William, 1949-1958 (Folder 15)
    - Drumright, Everett, 1954 (Folder 16)
    - Dulles, Allen, 1951-1959 (Folder 17)
    - Dulles, John Foster, 1951-1958 (Folder 18)
    - Dunn, James C., 1952-1954 (Folder 19)
    - Duranton, Roger, 1952-1954 (Folder 20)
    - Durbrow, Elbridge, 1951-1959 (Folder 21)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1951-1958 (Folder 22)
    - Eisenhower, Milton, 1954-1957 (Folder 23)
    - Elbrick, C. Burke, 1959 (Folder 24)
    - Emmerson, John K., 1955 (Folder 25)
    - Estes, Thomas, 1959 (Folder 26)
    - Fahey, Daniel, 1953 (Folder 27)
    - Fairbanks, Douglas, 1949 (Folder 28)
    - Farley, James, 1952-1959 (Folder 29)
    - Fullerton, Hugh, 1953-1959 (Folder 30)
    - Funk, Arthur, 1951-1953 (Folder 31)
    - Gibson, Hugh, 1953 (Folder 32)
    - Glover, Cato, 1957-1959 (Folder 33)
    - Greenwood, E.M., 1957-1958 (Folder 34)
    - Grew, Joseph C., 1952-1956 (Folder 35)
    - Gross, Ernest A., 1953-1954 (Folder 36)
    - Gruenther, Alfred, 1952-1959 (Folder 37)
    - Hammarskjold, Dag, 1953 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Handy, Thomas, 1951 (Folder 2)
    - Harrington, Julian, 1953-1955 (Folder 3)
    - Henderson, Loy, 1959 (Folder 4)
    - Herter, Christian, 1956-1959 (Folder 5)
    - Hickerson, John, 1953 (Folder 6)
    - Higgins, Frank, 1959 (Folder 7)
    - Higgins, Marguerite, 1953-1959 (Folder 8)
    - Hillenkoetter, R.H., 1951 (Folder 9)
    - Hobby, Oveta Culp, 1953 (Folder 10)
    - Hoffman, Paul G., 1954-1956 (Folder 11)
    - Hoover, Herbert C., 1955-1959 (Folder 12)
    - Hoover, Herbert, Jr., 1957-1959 (Folder 13)
    - Hoover, J. Edgar, 1959 (Folder 14)
    - Houghton, Amory, 1958-1959 (Folder 15)
    - Houghton, Amory, Jr., 1959 (Folder 16)
    - Howe, George, 1950 (Folder 17)
    - Hull, Cordell, 1950 (Folder 18)
    - Johnson, U. Alexis, 1953-1959 (Folder 19)
    - Johnston, Eric, 1953 (Folder 20)
    - Jones, Howard P., 1953-1959 (Folder 21)
    - Keeley, James H., 1954 (Folder 22)
    - Kennan, George, 1950-1957 (Folder 23)
    - Kennedy, John and Jacqueline, 1953-1955 (Folder 24)
    - Kennedy, Joseph P., 1953 (Folder 25)
    - King, Wunsz, 1952 (Folder 26)
    - Kirk, Alexander, 1951 (Folder 27)
    - Kocher, Eric, 1953 (Folder 28)
    - Kohlberg, Alfred, 1953 (Folder 29)
    - Laukhuff, Perry, 1953-1959 (Folder 30)
    - Leahy, William, 1950 (Folder 31)
    - Lichtenstein, Walter, 1953-1959 (Folder 32)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1953-1959 (Folder 33)
    - Lodge, John Davis, 1959 (Folder 34)
    - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1954-1959 (Folder 35)
    - Lyon, Cecil, 1959 (Folder 36)
    - MacArthur, Douglas, II, 1952-1959 (Folder 37)
    - Macmillan, Harold, 1949-1959 (Folder 38)
    - Mansfield, Mike, 1952-1953 (Folder 39)
    - Marshall, George, 1953-1955 (Folder 40)
    - Matthews, H. Freeman, 1951-1959 (Folder 41)
    - McClelland, Roswell, 1952-1953 (Folder 42)
    - McClintock, Robert, 1952-1959 (Folder 43)
    - McCloy, John J., 1953-1959 (Folder 44)
    - McCormick, Ken, 1950-1953 (Folder 45)
    - McGuire, Perkins, 1959 (Folder 46)
    - Menuhin, Yehudi, 1949-1959 (Folder 47)
    - Merrill, Eugene, 1952-1959 (Folder 48)
    - Mesta, Perle, 1952-1955 (Folder 49)
    - Middleton, George, 1950 (Folder 50)
    - Millard, Hugh, 1951-1954 (Folder 51)
    - Morris, Brewster, 1951-1959 (Folder 52)
    - Nixon, Richard M., 1956-1959 (Folder 53)
    - Norstad, Lauris, 1956 (Folder 54)
    - North African Economic Board, 1951-1958 (Folder 55)
    - Nuveen, John, 1951-1958 (Folder 56)
    - O'Brien, William G., 1955-1959 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - O'Donnell, E.J., 1958-1959 (Folder 2)
    - Oestreicher, Sylvan, 1950-1956 (Folder 3)
    - Offie, Carmel, 1950-1959 (Folder 4)
    - Okazaki, Eimatsu, 1953 (Folder 5)
    - Okazaki, Katsuo, 1952-1959 (Folder 6)
    - Oppenheimer, Fritz, 1952-1959 (Folder 7)
    - Pace, Frank, Jr., 1950-1951 (Folder 8)
    - Palmer, Ely, 1959 (Folder 9)
    - Platzner, Wilfried, 1959 (Folder 10)
    - Pogue, Forrest, 1951-1952 (Folder 11)
    - Radford, Arthur, 1952-1953 (Folder 12)
    - Rankin, Karl, 1953 (Folder 13)
    - Raymond, Arthur J., 1951 (Folder 14)
    - Reber, Samuel, 1951-1959 (Folder 15)
    - Reid, Ogden, 1959 (Folder 16)
    - Rhee, Syngman, 1952 (Folder 17)
    - Rheinstrom, H., 1956-1959 (Folder 18)
    - Riddleberger, James W., 1952-1959 (Folder 19)
    - Ridgway, Matthew, 1953-1955 (Folder 20)
    - Robertson, Walter, 1953-1959 (Folder 21)
    - Rockefeller, John D., III, 1952-1959 (Folder 22)
    - Romulo, Carlos, 1959 (Folder 23)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1959 (Folder 24)
    - Rose, France de, 1957-1959 (Folder 25)
    - Royall, Kenneth, 1949-1959 (Folder 26)
    - Rusk, Dean, 1952-1959 (Folder 27)
    - Sebald, William J., 1953 (Folder 28)
    - Sheean, Vincent, 1959 (Folder 29)
    - Skouras, Spyros, 1953-1959 (Folder 30)
    - Smith, Bernard, 1958-1959 (Folder 31)
    - Smith, W. Bedell, 1950-1955 (Folder 32)
    - Spellman, Francis Cardinal, 1951-1959 (Folder 33)
    - Stassen, Harold, 1955 (Folder 34)
    - Steedman, Alec, 1953 (Folder 35)
    - Steeves, John, 1954-1955 (Folder 36)
    - Stevens, Robert, 1959 (Folder 37)
    - Stevenson, Adlai, 1952 (Folder 38)
    - Sulzberger, Arthur H., 1952-1958 (Folder 39)
    - Taft, Orray, Jr., 1952-1959 (Folder 40)
    - Tanaka, Mitsuo, 1953 (Folder 41)
    - Taylor, Maxwell, 1953-1959 (Folder 42)
    - Thompson, Tyler, 1953 (Folder 43)
    - Tittmann, Harold H., 1954 (Folder 44)
    - Tong, Hollington, 1953-1955 (Folder 45)
    - Torrente, Henry de, 1955-1959 (Folder 46)
    - Truitt, Max, 1951 (Folder 47)
    - Truman, Harry, 1952 (Folder 48)
    - Voorhees, Tracy, 1950-1953 (Folder 49)
    - Wailes, Edward, 1953 (Folder 50)
    - Webb, James, 1951 (Folder 51)
    - Wedemeyer, Albert C., 1954 (Folder 52)
    - Wells, Gladys, 1953-1959 (Folder 53)
    - Weygand, Maxime, 1958 (Folder 54)
    - White, Thomas, 1958-1959 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Wiley, John C., 1951-1953 (Folder 2)
    - Williams, Jack S., 1952-1957 (Folder 3)
    - Williams, Margaret, 1952-1958 (Folder 4)
    - Williams, Walter, 1959 (Folder 5)
    - Willis, Frances, 1955 (Folder 6)
    - Wood, John, 1958-1959 (Folder 7)
    - Woodward, Robert, 1953-1959 (Folder 8)
    - Woodyear, William, 1952-1953 (Folder 9)
    - Wright, Jerauld, 1953-1959 (Folder 10)
    - Yosano, Shigeru, 1952 (Folder 11)
    - Yoshida, Shigeru, 1952-1959 (Folder 12)
    - Young, Kenneth, 1953-1958 (Folder 13)
  - Subject file. Printed material, reports, memoranda, correspondence, 1949-1959
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Folder 14)
    - WITHDRAWN. SECURITY CLASSIFIED MATERIAL (Folder 15)
    - Germany (Folder 16)
    - International relations (Folder 17)
    - Israeli-Arab settlement, 1955 (Folder 18)
    - Lebanon, 1958 (Folder 19)
    - Middle East (Folder 20)
    - Miscellany (Folder 21)
    - Repin, Ilya (Folder 22)
    - Report of the Conference on German External Debts, 1952 (Folder 23)
    - Russia - History. "The Will of Peter the Great" (Folder 24)
    - United Nations (Folder 25)
    - United States
      - WITHDRAWN. SECURITY CLASSIFIED MATERIAL (Folder 26)
      - Embassy, Belgium (Folder 27)
      - Embassy, Japan
        - Background information (Box 92, Folder 1-2)
        - Despatches (Folder 3)
        - Entertainment records (Folder 4-5)
        - Memoranda (Folder 6)
        - Miscellany (Folder 7)
      - Far East Command (Folder 8)
      - Foreign relations
        - General (Folder 9)
        - Japan - Treaties (Folder 10)
- Later Years I, 1959-1978 (Boxes 93-143)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, and office files from Robert Murphy's career as a business executive. Correspondence related to his appointment to the Presidential Transition Committee, 1968-1969, and office files from the Commission on the Organization of the Government for the Conduct of Foreign Policy, 1973-1974, are also included in this series; arranged by form or function.
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - 1960 (Box 93, Folder 1)
      - 1961 (Folder 2)
      - 1962 (Folder 3)
      - 1963 (Folder 4)
      - 1964 (Folder 5)
      - 1965 (Folder 6)
      - 1966 (Folder 7)